mountainroseherbs.com 2001-04-06

# Mountain Rose Herbs - Our Ethics...

**Our Ethics...**

**Organics**   
Currently we offer what we feel is one of the best selections of certified organic herbs. We are hopeful that one day soon all the products that you see throughout our catalog will be grown and sold certified organic. The items that are not certified organic are harvested in the wild with a few exceptions, thus liberating ourselves from commercial farming dependencies. In addition to this a good number of our products are grown biodynamic. To find out more about this please check the web for a multitude of biodynamic articles. We can never stress the importance of organics enough, so to make things simple here is a quick compendium of why the world need not just organic but **certified** organic. 

Conventional non-organaic crops require large amounts of synthetic chemicals and fertilizers which are directly sprayed on the crops or injected into the ground. This presents serious problems in the form of run off from the farms and it contaminates our ground water supply. This will also be fed to wildlife through what is known as bio-accumulation, forever changing the blueprints mother nature designed. It also neutralizes the composition of the soil creating an "addict"-like dependency for synthetic supplements which of course lead to an increased use in chemicals. With all of this in mind we also need to take into consideration that this is very questionable in regards to materials we put into our body, and more so ... materials we depend upon to heal our bodies. 

**Our Sources**   
One deciding factor in the products you see throughout our catalog is respect for workers, not just overseas but here in the U.S. as well. We have a strict policy that guarantees workers a fair market value for the goods they produce and that any items we purchase from countries outside of the U.S. have a clean human rights record. We have dropped items altogether and refused to carry particular products because laborers were not given an equal voice or a just salary. We also work meticulously with our sources to investigate the lands where plant materials are gathered to ensure that indigenous populations have not been mistreated, displaced or disrespected. We have even refused to carry products that would have exploited cheap labor in Mexico because of NAFTA policies! 

**Our Catalog**   
We send out two catalogues each year. Forty pages are made from 100% recycled newsprint and the eight center pages are 50% recycled print. The printing is done with soybean-based inks, and absolutely no petroleum or solvent-based solutions were used in the production of our catalogue. It's so clean it can be composted! At this time we have decided to stay away from glossy stock catalogue options because of the amount of chemicals needed to be used in the process. The findings were incredible! 

**Our Shipping Materials**   
Our packaging material is tediously collected from local businesses. We use clean Styrofoam peanuts as a cushion for your order, and gather boxes from several locations to be reused as shipping cartons and the bubble wrap used to protect breakables during transport is made from recycled plastic. If you cannot reuse or recycle these items please send them back to us. If you include your name, address, and "green circle" on a separate piece of paper, we will enter you in our monthly Green Circle drawing, where you will have the chance to win a $25 Mountain Rose Herbs gift certificate. The cost to mail these items back to us is minimal and will usually run $1-3 in postage fees. 

* * *

**Links to Information and Resources**

In this age of mushrooming giant corporations, where goods are produced in third-world countries, where people and land are exploited in the interest of increasing profits and shrinking responsibility, it is up to all of us to shop with integrity. Below are links to fabulous organizations that could use a hand cleaning things up. 

2017 Mission St., Rm. 303   
San Francisco, CA 94110   
(800) 497-1994 [http://www.globalexchange.org](http://www.globalexchange.org/)

Co-op America's National Green Pages   
1612 K St. NW #600   
Washington DC 20006   
(800) 584-7336   

New York   
(212) 242-3002 [http://www.nlcnet.org](http://www.nlcnet.org/)

1213 Race St.   
Philadelphia PA 19107   
(215) 563-7110 [http://www.wilpf.org](http://www.wilpf.org/)

(800) 326-0959 [http://www.greenpeaceusa.org](http://www.greenpeaceusa.org/)

**Our Privacy Policy** One of the hot topics with the online world is a company’s privacy policy. This is not revealing news for us. Since 1987 Mountain Rose Herbs has never sacrificed our customers personal information for the mere advantage of shortsighted financial gain. We have never sold, traded, or rented our mailing list or customer information. For this amount of dedication to our customer’s privacy, Mountain Rose Herbs received an honorable national award in 1995 for holding such a formidable business practice. 

With regards to your online privacy a large portion of companies have adopted a very benign business practice called customer "personalization" also known as "customization". What this means is that a companies server can install itself into your computer and retrieve what is known as "cookie" files. These files exist on practically every computer system. There the companies servers are fed data involving your web surfing habits, pages most viewed, items purchased, buying frequencies, personal attributes, downloads, etc. They use this information to place strategic banner ads on your browser, offer you items they think might entice you, greet you by name when you enter their site, and store personal information within their own database to help them with marketing, mailing lists, consumer demographics, buying habits, age range, etc. WE DO NOT USE THIS TACTIC. We do not collect your cookie files and do not intend to. Take a peak into your cookie files and you will see for yourself that Mountain Rose Herbs is nowhere to be found in there. 

We do not research your buying habits, we do not sell your buying habits, and most of all we do not transfer your online purchasing and personal information onto any other machine. Everything you have given us stays with us……….period. 

For more information on this please contact Shawn Donnille/Operations Manager at [ shawn@mountainroseherbs.com](mailto:shawn@mountainroseherbs.com), or the Webmaster, Ed Greenwood at [ webmaster@mountainroseherbs.com](mailto:webmaster@mountainroseherbs.com). 

* * *

**Go to top of page**

**Mountain Rose Herbs**   
20818 High St, North San Juan, CA 95960   
(800) 879-3337   
FAX - (510) 217-4012   
Outside USA - (530) 292-9138   

**Copyright 2000 Mountain Rose Herbs**
